# Arkady Miasnikov

(054) 4681517 | arkady.miasnikov@gmail.com

# Software Engineer experienced in leading development projects from inception to full implementation

Expertise in design and development of mission-critical real-time systems, firmware, multi-threaded applications, automated trading platforms, and web-based applications.

Practiced in pre-sales and post-sales support of Tier 1 telecom companies in Europe and North America. Technology-savvy with a broad business perspective, good interpersonal relations, and high attention to detail.

Tools & Technologies: Linux, Go, Python, C, C++11/14

# Professional Experience

# 2023-present: Software Engineer - Endotech

- Collaboratively designed and developed custom momentum indicators and signal filters for specific market conditions, enhancing trading performance.
- Translated and customized multiple indicators from PineScript to Go, improving their efficiency and functionality.
- Developed indicators that are a central part of the company's trading algorithms.

# 2022-2023: Software Engineer - HiAuto

- Participated in the maintenance of the computerized drive-thru order-taking system as part of an international team to ensure operational efficiency and reliability.
- Enhanced business analytics tools by integrating data and troubleshooting systems, improving decision-making processes.
- Ensured continuous operation of on-premises devices, addressing technical issues promptly.

#### 2018-2022: Software Engineer - Cyren

- Participated in the collaborative design and development of email and network security products, contributing to a increase in threat detection accuracy.
- Maintained a complex SaaS system, integrating a range of popular software products seamlessly.
- Developed advanced phishing and spam detection engines.
- Initiated and prepared multiple POCs, including headless browsers, image recognition services, fast Hamming distance calculations, and locality-sensitive hashing.

#### 2016-2018: Software Engineer - Secdo

 Defined, designed, and developed the Linux endpoint driver, enhancing system performance with minimal impact.

- Developed a solution to analyze millions of system events per second on multicore systems efficiently.
- Supported Windows endpoint software development, including kernel driver and user space code.
- Improved data processing performance and developed behavioral models for the security research team.

# 2012-2016: Software Engineer - Megabridge

- Developed a video monitoring and control system for HLS, including hardware verification and low-level embedded firmware development.
- Designed drivers and significant firmware components for the BDSL product line, including Java-based web management.
- Led bring-up projects for various HW platforms, customizing Linux root file systems using Yocto.
- Established the company's automatic build infrastructure and continuous integration system.

# 2009-2012: Software Engineer - Texas Instruments

- Developed firmware for 802.11 ASIC, including pre and post-silicon verification of WLAN devices.
- Participated in WLAN Linux kernel development and defined/developed utilities for firmware build and debug in Linux.
- Led a streamlining process that improved productivity by 30% by advocating the replacement of ClearCase with GIT.
- Established a wiki-based search system that improved access to the company's knowledge base.

### Education

B.A. in Business Administration - Netanya Academic College (2007-2009) Software Practical Engineer - Tel Aviv University School of Practical Engineering Physics Department - St. Petersburg State University (1987-1989)